[uplifting music]
[Lloyd] I take it you
got the same message?
From Master Wu?
Saying there'd be
special training today?
Yeah, we heard the same thing.
[Zane] I see you received
Master Wu's message
as well, Jay.
Uh, totally.
I wasn't playing
video games for so long,
my legs went numb
and I needed a walk.
That message, which
I absolutely got,
is definitely why I'm here.
Excellent. It is time
for an important lesson.
Today, we are going to dance.
[group groans]
Not more "Spin Harmony."
Come on, Master Wu,
you know I ran away
from that dancing school my
dad put me in when I was a kid.
Focus. Just like a warrior,
a dancer is completely
in tune with their body.
Dance will only improve
your fighting skills.
Plus, you might have
fun in the process.
-[record player clicks]
-[gentle waltz music]
Now, follow me. One, two,
three, one, two, three.
[gentle waltz music continues]
May I have this dance?
[chuckles] Sure.
[gentle waltz music continues]
I will love you forever, Nya.
[ominous music]
Jay! Jay!
Whoop!
[Ninja grunts]
Jay!
[Nya gasps]
[giggles]
Jay!
♪ Lost in the unknown
So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[flame roaring]
[calm music]
Lloyd, I saw Jay.
What? Where?
He went south, but I lost
him in the crowd. Come on!
[powerful music]
-[people chattering]
-Did he see you?
No, and I didn't see his
face, but I'm sure it was him.
I think. I don't know.
Maybe I'm just seeing things.
Jay's been missing
since the Merge.
I miss him so much.
We all do.
[calm music continues]
I know Zant-Tanz.
He doesn't have a cruel bone
in his body!
Actually, he doesn't have
any bones in his body,
but that's not the point.
I don't believe he was
behind those attacks,
either, but who was?
My guess, the same
person who's responsible
for attacking the Matriarch,
and his name rhymes with "paws."
Ras, I'm talking about Ras.
Yeah, I gathered that,
but Ras was also
attacked last night.
Right. Man, this whole
mystery-solving stuff is hard.
My parents were so good at it!
They'd probably solve
this thing in a day.
Have you asked the
other Ninja for help?
No, Lloyd made this my mission.
If I can't compete
in the tournament,
I'm determined to prove myself
by solving this mystery.
The safety of the Source
Dragons is at stake here.
-Come on, Riyu, time to
hunt for some clues.
-[Riyu grunts]
You're not the only ones with
a mystery to solve today.
In all these mystery books,
your dad and I are
always reading,
the first thing a detective does
is retrace the steps
of everyone involved.
Why do you think they do that?
'Cause it might lead to clues,
-to help the detective
solve the case?
-That's right!
Look at you, already a great
little detective, Arin.
[Riyu sniffing]
The attacker must've come
through here last night, Riyu.
We need to try and
retrace that bot's steps.
-[Riyu squawks]
-[gasps] You find something?
[Riyu continues
sniffing, squawks]
You found the same
scent as last night?
If we can figure out where
the attacker came from,
maybe we can figure out
who sent them.
-[Riyu continues sniffing]
-[dramatic music]
-[Riyu squawks]
-Dead end.
Wait. Some kind of symbol
scratched into the wall.
I wonder if this is a clue
to whoever sent the bot?
Let me copy it down.
Arin! What are you up to?
Oh, Frak, hey!
Riyu and I were
just, uh, well...
[chuckles] It's complicated
Ninja business, really.
[laughs] Do you
know how cool it is
you get to say stuff like that?
My master's been
training me hard,
but I'm taking a break
to grab a pie.
-Interested?
-[Riyu's stomach gurgling]
I might know a dragon who'd
be up for a pie or ten.
Let's go!
[bright music]
-[wondrous music]
-[Riyu slurping]
[Frak] I can't believe
what that Zant-Tanz guy
tried to pull last night.
-Attacker bots? Scary, right?
-[Riyu growling]
I don't think Zant-Tanz
was behind it.
He's not the aggressive type.
The guy's frightened by
sharp corners on tables.
But no one else
could have done it.
[Riyu sniffing]
-[Riyu growls]
-So, you gotta tell me,
how did you hook
up with the Ninja?
And do you freak out
about it every day?
Oh, pretty much.
Sora and I met Lloyd
while we were trying
to save Riyu here
from dragon hunters.
It's been a dream come true,
but it's also a lot of work.
Training can be hard.
Tell me about it.
You have to meet my master.
I was so clueless and
scared by my powers,
and he really helped me out.
He sounds awesome.
-[calm music]
-Wyldfyre?
Oh, hey, Arin, [laughs]
didn't see you there.
I'm just doing some mental
exercises on my own,
definitely not looking
for someone or anything.
This whole tournament
is tight, Uncle.
You're a control freak.
Your idea of control is
chaos, Roby. I don't like it.
Oh! [giggling] Hi, Roby.
I was just wandering
here randomly,
doing my own thing and not
looking for you at all,
but since I'm seeing you now,
I just wanted to say
I can't wait to help make
your tournament a success.
Oh, thanks. Uh,
Wyldfyre, isn't it?
[gasps] That's my name.
It's a dragon name.
I was raised by dragons,
but I'm not a dragon,
as you can see.
Why am I still talking?
Stop talking.
My uncle and I were, uh,
just about to check out
the games plaza before
the first event.
Wanna come with?
Yes, definitely!
I mean, I have a lot of
other things I could do,
but they can wait, let's go!
Am I reading into things
a bit too much here?
That that girl has
a huge crush on Roby?
She might as well
be wearing a T-shirt
that says "I heart Roby."
Having a crush is
the most normal thing
I've ever seen her do.
Hey, I better head off to
meet my team. Check ya later?
Oh, definitely!
Go compete!
[melancholy music]
[sighs] Must be nice having
a power to compete with.
[Riyu sighs and grumbles]
[whimsical music]
[Cole] Hmm.
-Huh?
Geo? What?
You're here?
My tournament invite
showed up after you left.
I figured you'd wind up
here, too, so I came.
This is amazing!
Come on,
I'm checking out the city
before the competition starts.
[dramatic music]
Whoa!
Check it out, apparently
this mech belonged
to a past Elemental
Master of Earth.
Someone you knew?
Huh, Elemental
Powers are usually
passed down from parents.
I got mine from my mom.
Maybe this was hers. Wow.
[dramatic music]
[furtive music]
[ominous music]
Last night at the banquet,
why did you ask me for my help?
What are you talking about?
I did no such thing.
But you did. How could
you not remember it?
If you think playing mind games
is going to help you
Ninja win the tournament,
you're about to be
proven brutally wrong.
[ominous music]
I saw that.
Does she suspect something?
I don't know.
We must be careful.
What are you up to, Jordana?
[mysterious music]
Frak? He's with them?
[sinister music]
[Ninjas grunting]
[calm music]
[panting] Arin! You're
not gonna believe this.
That they have
Merlopian Cream pies here?
I know! I had three of them!
What? No!
Your old friend, Frak,
he's on Ras' team.
No way, that can't be true.
I saw it with my own eyes.
[Riyu growling]
You think so too, Riyu?
But Frak is a great guy!
You must've seen something
else and got confused.
I didn't. And I wouldn't
lie to you, Arin.
We better head over
to the games plaza.
First event's
coming up, and Roby,
trying to make everything
as "exciting as possible,"
won't tell anyone
who's competing until
the event itself.
-[Arin and Sora sighing]
-[Riyu growls]
[calm music]
[ominous music]
[Zarkt] Why the delay?
What's taking so long?
[sinister music]
My patience is wearing thin.
[suspenseful music]
You know how one of the
five made it out of here,
but we've only ever
seen three in here?
Guess that sleeping one
is the last of them.
[Bonzle] Sounds like
they're talking to someone.
But who? And how?
Make haste.
The sooner we are free,
the sooner our brutal
dominance can continue.
[ominous music]
They found a way to talk
to someone on the outside
who could free them?
We gotta check it out.
[powerful music]
-[bright music]
-Hey, hey, looking
good, looking good!
All engagement is
good engagement.
All right, bubbles!
Remember, play to the crowds.
The tournament is
and always has been
about the honor of
Elemental Battle.
It is not "hot."
You're not hot.
This is not how
your father ran it.
That's the point.
Hi again, Roby! Hi!
[whimsical music]
-[Cinder grunts]
-[Wyldfyre] Oh!
Oops. Sorry.
[Wyldfyre] That was
on purpose, Cinder!
So? What are you
gonna do about it?
You and your little
Ninja friends gonna cry?
Keep talking and you'll be
the one crying, tears of fire!
Hey, hey, hey! Calm it down!
-[Wyldfyre growls]
-Tournament rules, remember?
Any battle outside the games
will lead to expulsion!
[Wyldfyre growls]
[Wyldfyre grunts]
[dramatic music]
Remember, we aren't here
just to win.
We're competing
'cause we believe
whoever's threatening the
Source Dragons is here to win
and gain control of
all Elemental Powers.
The fate of the entire
Merged Lands is in our hands.
Yeah, you should all just use
Rising Dragon technique
from the start.
Plow through everyone.
No, Wyldfyre, this is a
Tournament of Elements.
Rising Dragon comes
from Spinjitzu
and should only be
used to defend oneself.
Like if Ras' team
uses Shatterspin?
Exactly, the Motion
Source Dragon
wanted us to compete honorably,
and that's what we're gonna do.
[inspiring music]
[all] Ninja, go!
Welcome, all you peeps
to the starting event
of the first Roby-Certified
Tournament of the Sources.
And this first game, we're
kicking it old-school.
[crowd cheering]
One-on-one, arena combat,
no holds barred!
In the grand tradition of the
Tournament of the Sources,
honor and sportsmanship are
our--
Ugh, you're making this sound
like boring old-school,
Uncle Bleckt, listen.
Our first competitor
is cold as ice
but computes twice as nice,
Zane, the Titanium Ninja!
-Come on, Zane. You got this.
-You can do it!
Facing off against Zane,
he's dark, mysterious,
and oh-so-dangerous, the
Master of Reflex himself, Zur!
[crowd cheering]
I am limber. I am loose.
-[Zur whooshing]
-I am in trouble.
[Lloyd] Don't worry, Zane!
He's got fast reflexes, but
ice can slow down anything!
Honored guests and Masters!
Who's ready for the
epicness to begin?
-Yeah!
-[bell clangs]
[crowd cheering and applauding]
-[dramatic music]
-[competitors grunting]
[beams hissing]
-[ice crunches]
-[fist thuds]
-[crowd cheering]
-[suspenseful music]
-[Zur thuds]
-[beam hisses]
-Ooh!
[suspenseful music]
[Zane roars]
[dramatic music]
-[Zane shouts]
-[crowd cheering and applauding]
We have a victor! Zur wins!
What an incredible battle!
Intense!
Time for the first
Elemental Transition!
Behold, the Element Cup!
Now, Zane, if you would.
-[beam sizzling]
-[dramatic music]
Like every game that
has gone before,
the winner gets the Elemental
Power of the defeated
to carry into their
next competition.
[triumphant music]
[crowd cheering and applauding]
Did Zane's ice melt
unnaturally quickly?
Looked quick to me.
Told you ya shoulda
used Rising Dragon.
Maybe Wyldfyre's right.
She is not. Your
leadership is sound, Lloyd.
It is not the Ninja way
to use excessive force
to fight unfairly.
That was a noble battle
that I unfortunately lost,
putting our mission in jeopardy.
Now I can only spectate
until my powers return
after the final game.
You did the best
you could, Zane.
No one said this
was gonna be easy.
I wonder who's up next?
Please welcome to the arena,
she's slick, she's cool,
and she's well-hydrated!
Nya, Elemental Master of Water!
I had to ask.
Get psyched, Nya.
Ready to go, ready to win.
Looks like Ras might be
coaching your opponent.
Whoever it is, I can take 'em.
[suspenseful music continues]
Jay?
[dramatic music]
The most shocking competitor
in the tournament,
Jay Walker, Elemental
Master of Lightning!
-[lightning sizzling]
-[dramatic music]
[crowd cheering and applauding]
[dramatic music continues]
Jay! I knew I saw you.
What are you talking about?
I've never seen you
before in my life.
Jay could never forget
Nya, or any of us!
Is that some kind of fake Jay?
Some loser in a Jay wig?
We don't know what
happened to Jay
after he disappeared
in the Merge.
[suspenseful music]
I knew the Ninja would
never see this coming.
[mysterious music]
[dramatic music]
It's time now for--
[tower clanking]
The Tower Battle!
The first to reach
the top of the tower
and get that glorious
blinged-out dagger
will be hey-o, winner!
[crowd cheering and applauding]
[dramatic music]
Lloyd, I can't fight him!
I don't think we have a choice.
[bell clangs]
Jay! It's me, Nya!
Is that supposed to mean
something to me, lady? Hiya!
-Ooh!
-[Nya thuds]
-[team gasps]
-[crowd cheers]
[panting] Jay!
[competitors grunting]
Nya, focus on the dagger!
[suspenseful music]
[Jay grunting]
Jay!
You had a clear shot
and didn't take it!
Are you a terrible Ninja?
I don't wanna hurt you.
We care too much for each other!
Speak for yourself, lady.
Ooh-ah!
-[Jay grunting]
-Oh, look out!
My Master, Ras, told
me you'd lie to me,
try to use mind games on me.
You won't shake my confidence!
I don't believe a word you say!
[grunts] Ras is
the one lying to you!
You're a Ninja who
disappeared after the Merge!
Jay, you're the love of my life.
Ugh, as if! Ras
told me the truth.
I was a great warrior,
fighting alongside my
Master in the Wyldness.
When the Merge happened,
I lost my memory
and ended up in some place
called The Administration.
[mysterious music]
The Administration?
Jay is Agent Walker?
[dramatic music]
-[both grunting]
-[fists thudding]
I escaped from there.
Then Lord Ras found me
and rescued me!
[Nya grunts]
I owe it to Ras to win this
tournament, whatever it takes.
Jay, no! Don't do that!
[ominous music]
He's gonna shatter his goodness!
I'm afraid he already has.
[ominous music continues]
[gong clangs]
[dramatic music]
-[crowd cheering]
-Ooh-ah!
-[fist thuds]
-[Nya grunts and thuds]
-[foot thuds]
-[Nya thuds]
[dramatic music]
You don't leave me
any choice, Jay.
[inspiring music]
[triumphant music]
-[Jay shouts]
-[crowd cheering and applauding]
-Wow!
-Whoo-hoo!
Wow, didn't a super-smart
and good-looking Ninja here
say Rising Dragon
technique would be epic?
[triumphant music]
[crowd cheering and applauding]
[triumphant music continues]
-Yes!
-Whoo-hoo!
[Ras growls]
[triumphant music continues]
We have a winner!
Nya, Master of Water!
Woot-woot! Spa-lash!
-[tower clanking]
-[triumphant music continues]
[beam sizzles]
[crowd cheering and applauding]
The thrills keep coming!
Jay is now without
his Elemental Powers,
and Nya now controls
water and lightning!
Show us, Nya!
[triumphant music continues]
-[calm music]
-[crowd cheering]
I didn't rescue you so you
could disappoint me, Jay.
I do not tolerate failure.
I'm sorry, Lord Ras.
Sorry is not good enough.
[calm music continues]
She won. We're doing what the
Source Dragon asked of us.
So why does this
just feel empty?
Because we might have won
the match, but we lost Jay.
Jay, I know you
lost your memory,
but you need to know the truth.
I love you.
I will always love you.
And I will always hate you.
[mysterious music]
[Ras growls]
[Roby whooshes]
[eerie music]
Is she asleep, or...
She's breathing, but she's
totally out of it or something.
Hello? Boo!
Nope, she's out.
What is that? Lint?
Huh, must be scales from Riyu,
from when he tried to keep me
from getting sucked
into the portal.
[liquid bubbling]
Those scales, you have
a physical connection
to someone outside of here.
Maybe we can
communicate with Riyu.
[eerie music]
[fireworks booming
and whistling]
[Kai] Riyu?
[Riyu whimpers]
[Kai]
Riyu, can you hear us?
-It's Kai and Bonzle. Hello?
-[Riyu squawks]
[dramatic music]